<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-button library="Buttons">
	<name>pageLength</name>
	<summary>Button collection that will control the DataTables' page length</summary>
	<since>1.1.0</since>

	<description>
		It is quite common to have four table control and information elements around a DataTable - one in each corner. DataTables' default display as a page length control in the top left, which where Buttons are often inserted, resulting in the page length list being dropped to keep the control elements limited to four.

		The default page length list could of course be inserted back into the document by simply adding the `l` option to the `dt-init dom` configuration, but it might look visually confusing.

		As a result Buttons offers this `b-button pageLength` button type as part of its core software which functions as a direct replacement to the DataTables default length list. This allows page length control to be retained while enjoying full styling integration with Buttons.

		This button will read the configuration used for the DataTables `dt-init lengthMenu` configuration option, so the same configuration can be used for this buttons as well as DataTables' default page length control.
	</description>

	<extend>collection</extend>

	<option type="string|object|function" name="text" default="{'-1': 'Show all rows', _: 'Show %d rows'}">
		The button's display text. By default this is a function that uses the object shown, where the `%d` value is replaced by the result from `dt-api page.len()` (i.e. the current page length). The text can be configured using this option (see `b-init buttons.buttons.text`) or the `buttons.pageLength` option of the DataTables `dt-init language` object.
	</option>

	<option type="string" name="className" default="buttons-collection buttons-page-length">
		The button's class name. See `b-init buttons.buttons.className` for details.
	</option>

	<option type="function" name="action">
		Show the collection to allow page length selection.
	</option>


	<example title="DataTables initialisation: Show the `pageLength` button with default options"><![CDATA[

$('#myTable').DataTable( {
	dom: 'Bfrtip',
	buttons: [ 'pageLength' ]
} );

]]></example>

	<example title="Page length button with `dt-init lengthMenu` specified"><![CDATA[

$('#myTable').DataTable( {
	dom: 'Bfrtip',
	lengthMenu: [
		[ 10, 25, 50, -1 ],
		[ '10 rows', '25 rows', '50 rows', 'Show all' ]
	],
	buttons: [
		'pageLength'
	]
} );

]]></example>

	<example title="Custom language string for the collection button (note the use of an object to allow the `-1` value (i.e. show all) to be specified as a language string)"><![CDATA[

$('#myTable').DataTable( {
	dom: 'Bfrtip',
	language: {
		buttons: {
			pageLength: {
				_: "Afficher %d éléments",
				-1: "Tout afficher"
			}
		}
	},
	buttons: [
		'pageLength'
	]
} );

]]></example>
</dt-button>