<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-example table-type="ajax" order="7">

<css lib="datatables buttons"/>
<js lib="jquery datatables buttons jszip pdfmake vfsfonts buttons-html5">
<![CDATA[

$(document).ready(function() {
	var buttonCommon = {
		exportOptions: {
			format: {
				body: function ( data, row, column, node ) {
					// Strip $ from salary column to make it numeric
					return column === 5 ?
						data.replace( /[$,]/g, '' ) :
						data;
				}
			}
		}
	};

	$('#example').DataTable( {
        ajax: '../../../../examples/ajax/data/objects.txt',
        columns: [
            { data: 'name' },
            { data: 'position' },
            { data: 'office' },
            { data: 'extn' },
            { data: 'start_date' },
            { data: 'salary' }
        ],
		dom: 'Bfrtip',
		buttons: [
			$.extend( true, {}, buttonCommon, {
				extend: 'copyHtml5'
			} ),
			$.extend( true, {}, buttonCommon, {
				extend: 'excelHtml5'
			} ),
			$.extend( true, {}, buttonCommon, {
				extend: 'pdfHtml5'
			} )
		]
	} );
} );

]]>
</js>

<title lib="Buttons">Format output data - export options</title>

<info><![CDATA[

Buttons has two different methods that can be used to format the data exported differently from the data that is shown in the table: [orthogonal options](outputFormat-orthogonal.html) and formatting functions as shown in this example. They both achieve basically the same thing in different ways: namely modification of the output data.

Formatting functions for export buttons are specified by assigning a function to one (or more) of the `format` object of the `exportOptions` object. Three formatting functions can be used: `header`, `footer` and `body`. This is the primarily advantage of using formatting functions over orthogonal data - the header and footer can also be formatted using this method (of course orthogonal and this formatting function method can both be used together if you prefer!).

This example uses a `body` formatting function to remove the `$` and `,` characters from the final column to make it a numeric value in the output data. Since this is common to all three export buttons used, the function is placed into an object that is reused by each button - simply to save repeating the same code! This is not required, but it can be a useful technique.

]]></info>

</dt-example>

